# SIDDHARTH BISOYI



♠ Munnekollal, 560037 Bengaluru \$\square\$ 8093069220

siddharthbisoyi2@gmail.com

I'm a Product/Project Solution consultant and a Developer with an experience in working for Wipro Technologies and it helped me a lot in making myself utilize and hone my skills to the best. I have worked on many real time projects and received a lot of recognition for the same. I have **4 years experience**, working in E-Commerce and Banking Domain. Investing my time on creating

/developing /innovating is a passion for me.

Until recently, I was working on lot of research related to exploration of IAAS provided by cloud solutions on how we can automate various modules for a specific domain including code Development, ORM, Infrastructure. Focus was more on Microservice architecture.

Colleagues know me as a highly diligent person, who can always be trusted to come up with a new approach. I like spending lot of time knowing everything about the topic I am working on, it always makes the work more interesting .I'm at my best collaborating with others while working.

I'm open for opportunities to contribute and learn, I can be reached either through this profile or by mail at <a href="mailto:siddharthbisoyi2@gmail.com">siddharthbisoyi2@gmail.com</a></a>

### **SKILLS**

Java Expert

Microservice Experienced

**Springboot** Expert

**Database Technologies (with** 

ORM frameworks) Expert

AWS Cloud Experienced

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Aug 2020 - Present

**Lead Developer** 

Wipro Technologies, Bengaluru

#### Best Buy - One Super APP

Role: Developer and Consultant

Description: Integrating all platforms (retail, daily etc) to a single

platform.

Lead Developer Jan 2020 - Jul 2020

Wipro Technologies, Bengaluru

Best Buy - Backend Architecture

Revamp

Role: Developer and Consultant

Description: Revamp of e-commerce technology from Oracle ATG to smaller components of

microservices.

Lead Developer Jul 2019 - Dec 2019

Wipro Technologies, Bengaluru

Best Buy: Login Module (Common across platforms)

Role: Developer

Description: Login Module which uniquely identifies a user across platforms and makes common string between the platforms for the user. This also manages the user session with help of various

user use case JWT tokens.

Project Engineer Jan 2019 - Jun 2019

Wipro Limited, Bengaluru

Project: Push Notification (Capital One)

Role: Developer

Description: As a UK mandate all the digital transactions done by a customer using MasterCard, should be notified by notification on the details of the transaction done on their mobile app.

Responsible for creating the full stack infrastructure in AWS which includes EC2, RDS, ELB,

Lambda, Route53, ASG, IAM, S3, Aurora DB, SNS. Integrating with Master Card API, UrbanAirship

API for sending push notification.

Project Engineer Jan 2018- Dec 2018

Wipro Limited, Bengaluru

Project: Digital Card (Capital One)

Role: Developer

Description: Capital One project comes under the Banking & Financial domain. Our project is basically a credit card acquisition project, where we have designed the various processes required to

provide the credit card to the customer.

Project Engineer Dec 2016 - Dec 2017

Wipro Limited, Bengaluru

Project: Push Notification (Capital One)

Role: Developer

Description: Walmart Project comes under Retail and e-commerce domain. There are many sub project under Walmart for e-commerce website for various countries such as Mexico and Chile. The technologies used are Spring, Hibernate, JBOSS server and React JS. Also was working on ELK

stack for log monitoring and analytics for financial and app support team.

## **EDUCATION AND QUALIFICATIONS**

**B.Tech** Mar 2011 - Mar 2015

National Institute of Science and Technology, Berhampur

B. Tech (Computer Science and Engineering) from National Institute of Science and Technology, Odisha (Biju Patnaik University of Technology) in 2015.

#### **INTERESTS**

Participating in Athletic events, Playing drums, Table Tennis, Cooking